Good morning. It's Wednesday, October
22nd, and you're watching the program
with Ted R and John Kiryaku back
stateside where he belongs.
>> Finally.
>> Thank you so much for uh joining us.
Thank Please like, follow, and share the
show, John. It's really good to see you
again.
>> Good to see you, Ted. Glad to be back.
>> Robbie held down the fort while you were
gone.
>> I appreciate it very much, Robbie. And
uh so um yeah, let's uh By the way,
Robbie has some housekeeping to uh take
care of. So let's go ahead and pop him
in. Rahi, Robbie.
>> Yeah. What's up?
>> So I'm back in my appropriate place in
the background. Rob belongs. So I can't
break people's brains anymore with real
right-wing populism. Uh so just a quick
thing about YouTube for those of you who
are over there. Super chats and
memberships have been restored. So, if
y'all want to support the work that John
and Ted are doing, uh, you are able to
do that now on YouTube in addition to
the PayPal and in addition to the Rumble
and, uh, it's really all I've got.
>> Okay. Uh, thanks, Robbie. See you later.
Let me know about ads. Okay. Okay. So,
uh, we are here Monday through Friday,
9:00 am Eastern time. That's the regular
time. Uh, John, do you wanna how did you
survive the tarantulas and the uh and
the the canceled flights and the snakes
and the mosquitoes and the heat and the
no air conditioning?
>> Who moves into
the southernmost tip of the Baja
Peninsula
and builds a resort with no air
conditioning?
>> Now that's insane. It it's insane. And
why would you build a resort in a place?
Well, it's very beautiful. It truly is.
It's very beautiful. Palm trees
everywhere. Those big sagoro cactuses
with the arms, you know, they're
everywhere.
>> And and that's where Jacusto did most of
his diving. He called it uh the world's
aquarium, which everybody's very proud
of down there.
>> But I saw wildlife there, Ted. Half the
time I didn't know what the heck I was
looking at. The other half of the time I
didn't want to see it.
>> Snakes,
>> tarantulas, the snake.
>> I can count on one hand the number of
snakes that I saw in the first, you
know, 60 and a half years of my life
growing up in Pennsylvania. Um, and they
were garder snakes and black snakes.
>> Sure,
>> no big deal. These were freaking
rattlesnakes and they're everywhere.
I I saw I had to Google it and see what
the heck I was looking at. It was called
the the California ratnake.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Things are big, too.
>> The rat snakes aren't going to do
anything to you. No.
>> But then the scorpions, we were warned
in an email before we went down there
not to ever go barefoot. Okay, you're at
the beach for God's sake.
>> That's crazy.
>> Never go barefoot. Well, I never did.
And thank God I did. And I have this
habit like most people my age I would
suspect where I get up in the middle of
the night. I want to get a drink of
water or something.
>> Well, my little mini fridge was outside.
>> Oh
>> yeah. So I'd have to like shake out my
shoes to make sure there are no
scorpions or tarantulas in there
>> and then put the shoes on and then go
outside. But I had to have a flashlight
with me to make sure that the scorpions
and tarantulas aren't on my mini fridge,
which the tarantula was on my mini
fridge one night at 3:00 a.m.,
>> man.
>> Oh, it it's you don't get used to it.
You just get
>> tarantulas spin webs or not?
>> Not that not that I ever saw.
>> Yeah.
>> They they'll attack and and sting
something or bite it
>> if they consume it. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But even to eat, they'll eat that.
I'll tell you, I saw a deer. It was the
biggest freaking deer I ever saw in my
life, but it was completely gray.
>> Huh.
>> Yeah.
>> There's a lot of variety in deers,
right? Like those um like the key de
like the key deer in the deer. Very
tiny.
>> Tiny. Yeah.
>> There there's the Outer Banks deer in
North Carolina. Very tiny. This thing
was like the size of a of a mule deer.
You know, mu deer out west.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Big giant, but completely gray. Road
runners everywhere.
>> Those are cool.
>> Never saw one flying just running down
the road. Sometimes with as many as a
dozen pals of his
>> running down the road.
>> But it was the scorpions and the
tarantulas that really got to me because
they're everywhere.
>> Yeah. Like I've I've seen those um
images like where they use fluorescent
lights in the desert, right?
>> Let's see where the scorpions are. And
it's like they're everywhere. Like
everywhere.
>> Everywhere. It's it's awful. Awful.
>> You know, you know what's like that and
nobody thinks about this is Bali. Bali
has a lot of things that bite and sting
and hurt you.
>> I don't get the I don't get the uh the
appeal. I don't understand the appeal.
>> Another thing too was the road. And I'm
going to put Eric with the road.
So
>> Afghanistan,
>> I Jeff Fehee is the star of the movie
that I was in and is an easily
recognizable face if you just Google
Jeff Fehee. He and Tyrell Vanto, Jesse's
son, drove me to the airport early one
morning to go to do the Joe Rogan show.
So, hurricane um I forget who uh
hurricane uh Loretta or whatever the
heck it was. I I I don't remember.
>> Tarantula
>> had had come through and it washed out
the road.
And so they were like, you know, buddy,
you may not make it. We're not sure we
can make it. We didn't go 100 feet and
the road just didn't exist. It had just
washed away.
And we had to drive up this dune over
cactuses and animals are just jumping
out of the way. And it took us to go the
35 miles took us almost two hours and
then those poor guys had to drive back.
>> Jesus. Yeah.
>> I know about those roads.
>> Jee said to me um he said, "I was just
in Afghanistan six weeks ago and the
roads aren't this bad in Afghanistan." I
said, "I know. I I've been a million
times in Afghanistan.
>> They used to be. They before 2005 they
were.
>> Yeah,
>> but this was bad. Anyway, the important
thing is
>> I got to be in a real Hollywood movie,
Ted.
>> Like a real honest to god Hollywood
movie.
>> Is it going to be in theaters or is it
like a
>> straight to streaming kind of thing?
>> They're in talks with Netflix to to sell
it to Netflix. Um the editing is going
to be done by April. Then they're going
to lay over the soundtrack and it should
be ready to ready to watch um by July or
August.
>> Fantastic.
>> And that was that was really fun. Great
group of people.
>> Obviously, it's impossible to tell. I
used to be friends with a film director
>> and he you know he told me like you
don't really know what you have until
you get in there.
>> I asked the same question. I asked Jeff,
he's been in like 280 movies and TV
series. And I said, Jeff, do you know
when what you're working on is is good?
And he said, "No, you don't." He said,
"What what we tell ourselves,
>> right? Sometimes, you know, you you've
got lightning in a bottle, but not
usually."
>> You know, and if Scorsese is directing
it and Pacino's in it or whatever. Sure.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Yeah. He said, "What we tell ourselves
is
just to be proud. If if you're proud of
the of the job that you did, then that's
good enough because it's really not
possible to know if it was good enough.
>> Sometimes your best moments end up on
the cutting room floor."
>> Yeah, it's interesting. Um, thank you
for the donation, USX A-Rod. What are
the long-term ramifications of Marco
Rubio agreeing to send US informants to
El Salvador essentially going back on
agreements made with the informants?
>> Great question, man. When I read that, I
was absolutely appalled.
What that is essentially is a death
sentence. So he offered to rat out all
of our informants in exchange for the El
Salvadorans
uh allowing us to lock people up in
their in their gulag. That's really what
it came down to.
>> Sec absolutely chilling.
So yeah, I mean I mean the thing is um
there's always going to be another
sucker who's willing to work with the
US, but I you would think that over time
people might become more more skeptical.
Um so also uh Declar Robbie, I agree
with this argument. This is from
yesterday. The immigration laws should
be followed, but this Trump initiative
has almost nothing to do with
immigration. It's about shutting down
descent on behalf on his behalf. I I
would agree with that.
>> Yeah.
>> Nicholas Franos is asking you, John, was
Afghanistan more comfortable.
>> Sounds like it. I mean, I've been to
Afghanistan a bunch of times. I mean,
uh, the last few times were, you know,
um, bite-free. I didn't There were no
Well, first of all, there are no
tarantulas in
>> I never saw a snake there either.
>> I saw a snake, but I saw hundreds of
foxes.
>> Desert foxes. They come out of their
their dens when the sun goes down. You
can see their eyes shining off in the
distance.
>> They're not dangerous. Marmets. There's
lots of marmets.
>> And they had marmets down there in Baja
as well. Saw dozens of them. Um that's a
good question. You know, the the first
couple times I went to Afghanistan, um I
just slept in a tent with everybody
else. I mean, there was once where I
actually had my own tent, so I was, you
know, living high on the hog. Um, and
then once we got a serious foothold
there,
um, I'd stay in the officer's quarters
in, uh, at Bram.
>> And then when I went as a private
citizen to get those little kids out who
had who had starred in, um, the
Kiterunner,
>> uh, I stayed at, um, one of the big
Afghan hotels. And it was like any, you
know, three-star hotel.
>> Yeah.
>> That I stayed in anywhere else. this
resort in in Baja, it was built by a
group of hippies uh as a commune. Uh
>> the leader of
>> that explains a lot. That explains the
new
>> the ad to read. So,
>> okay. Oh, you
>> let me get that. Let me pop that out
because the clock starts ticking. You
bet.
>> Did you know the biggest threat to your
retirement is not something that's
talked about often? Our increased
longevity in America means default
retirement accounts like IAS, 401ks, and
TSPs may not suffi suffice. If you have
over $100,000 in your retirement
account, get instant access to a free
two-minute report from Augusta Precious
Metals that reveals the one step you can
take to secure your financial future.
Text safe to 35052
today.
>> Excellent. Um um also in answer to a
couple of people's questions um
uh about foxes there there was a fox
that would come Oh no no no the
compound. So the the sort of head of the
of the hippies was the daughter of
Thomas Hart Benton the the famous author
of 20th or I'm sorry artist the from the
early to mid 20th century. Um,
you know, we were joking with them. Four
of them were still there when we first
arrived and then they left. So, the
whole place was was ours. But, um, they
built it in the in the 60s, starting in
the 60s. And and the guy said, you know,
we weren't a cult. People accused us of
being a cult. We're just a bunch of
like-minded left-wing long-haired freaky
people, you know, from Los Angeles. But
they were also very skilled. One of them
was a an architect, one of them was a
builder. And so Thomas Hartbettton's
daughter had plenty of money. They built
this gorgeous resort. It's got about a
dozen different buildings. And um and
they just ended up living in it most of
the time and renting out rooms to scuba
divers. Otherwise,
the thing is is that there's literally
nothing to do there unless you're a
scuba diver. M
>> and then even if you are a scuba diver,
there are signs around like beware of
rockfish. They will sting you through
your flippers and you will
>> you're not even safe in the water. My
understanding I'm you know as you know
John I'm a scuba diver and my
understanding about Baja is that it's
kind of like a completely binary thing.
You're either g it's deep water. You
don't really see much. If you do see
something it's the it's a whale shark
which is something all divers like want
to see. Right. And and that's that's
what most people go down there to see
are the whale sharks.
>> Yeah. But you might not see [__] You
might you'll see either nothing at all.
Uh you know, you won't even see an angel
fish or you'll see a whale shark,
>> right?
>> So it's like that's, you know, that's
what it that's what it's all about.
Chad, we got a lot of news to talk
about. We're talking Ukraine and Russia,
the shutdown. Uh believe it or not,
there is really things are getting real
there. Uh Venezuela and Israel. What do
What do you want to do first? Yeah,
let's do Venezuela first because I think
that that's, you know, there's there's
some immediacy there that that we
legitimately should be should be um
worried about. By all accounts, Ted, it
looks like Donald Trump is planning some
sort of imminent military action in
Venezuela.
>> It definitely looks like it.
>> It really does. We don't have ground
troops in the area. Although Venezuela
is so close that it wouldn't be hard to
get ground troops there once something
were to take place.
>> But wouldn't it take a while though? Cuz
it's like
>> Yeah. There's no infrastructure for
them.
>> I mean it's Yeah. I mean basically it
would be an amphibious invasion like
D-Day, right? Wouldn't it be? I mean
>> which is what they've tried which is
what they've tried twice in Venezuela
already. You remember these these bozos
who got wrapped up, you know, as they
were coming ashore.
>> Yep. just like Bay Day of Figs 2.0.
>> One of them actually emailed me a couple
of weeks ago saying, "Hey, I really want
to be on your show. I want to blow the
whistle on communism in Venezuela." I'm
like, "Yeah, you're you're not a
whistleblower. No, you're not coming on
my show." So, um I I think that that
what you wrote
half an hour ago is correct. I think
we're looking at some sort of amphibious
assault. I think that we're looking at
an air war and uh you know it's funny
Ted the idea behind all this is
apparently what the idea was behind u
George W. Bush's uh invasion of of Iraq
that you you bomb the [__] out of a
country and then of course in your logic
the people will rise up against their
leader because that's what will make the
Americans start bombing and then they
overthrow him and then they throw
flowers at us when we cross the border
and everybody lives happily ever
>> and we have a free trade agreement for
hundreds of
>> and then we have a free trade agreement
and that never ever ever happens.
>> I mean, how how popular do you think
Nicolas Maduro is? I mean, I don't think
that really matters much, but I'm just
curious, you know?
>> Yeah. I don't I don't think it matters
much either. I I think he's less popular
than my than my friends on the left
believe he is.
>> He's not Hugo Chavez.
>> He's not Hugo Chavez. No, he's not.
>> Who was really popular?
>> Yeah. You know, when I was working on
the Senate Foreign Relations Committee
staff in back in 2009, uh I
>> Bay of Piglets. Hilarious.
>> That's really what it would be. That's
that's I wish I had thought of that. Um
Maduro was credibly
accused of of looking the other way
as drugs were transiting Venezuela bound
for Africa. We've talked about this
before. And then they're they're picked
up in um Giddy Basau and then from Gide
Basau they're put on camels and just
walked up this ancient Tarig smuggling
route to to Morocco and then
>> emissaries,
>> right? And then transferred to Europe.
So they're not even American drugs.
They're not even drugs that enter the
United States.
>> Fentinel is what's killing Americans.
>> Fentinel. We should be we should be
talking to the Mexicans. we should be
threat Chinese, which we are.
>> But this Venezuela thing,
>> I mean, you know, Robbie faciciously, I
hope faciticiously suggested that we
invade Mexico. I'm like, we already took
half their country. Um, but like um you
know, but I mean like we have
cooperation. Why aren't considering that
we do have good cooperation between
Mexican and American law enforcement and
intelligence very good cooperation? Why
aren't we making more progress in in in
keeping in stemming the flow across the
border?
>> Because even the Mexican government, the
federales who by all accounts are, you
know, great gung-ho
working for the right reasons,
>> incorruptible,
>> incorruptible. That's why they're
successful. But even the federales
have, you know, two hands tied behind
their backs,
>> which is why
>> just because the the cartels are too
strong.
>> So So basically there's just like it's
an it's an internal Yeah.
>> military force.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> So basically the government doesn't just
just doesn't control certain parts of
Mexico where they are.
>> You know, Ted,
I know you've been to Mexico many times.
I've been to Mexico many times. I've
been all over Mexico. I love it, too.
The only place I haven't been is Chapas,
and I' I'd love to see it.
>> Me neither.
>> But the thing is is,
>> you know, we
we should have been helping the Mexicans
develop their economy for the last
hundred years.
>> True.
>> And we haven't. We've punished them.
We've tried to keep them out, force them
out.
We've supported and we've supported the
most retrograde
factions in their in their political
scheme
>> without a doubt.
>> I mean that basically four we allowed
four families to run the own entire
economy.
>> Exactly.
>> So
>> exactly. Yeah. It's just like Haiti. We
we lament like oh poor Haiti. Oh we wish
we could help Haiti.
>> Hardworking, very intelligent people who
would do great if we just left them the
[__] alone. Yeah. Um,
>> John, right?
>> Good question from Real Real and thanks
for the two bucks. John, last week, uh,
Trump authorized covert CIA operations
in Venezuela. I've been dying to talk to
you about this for three for three days.
Uh, what are some examples and of of
like what what would that look like? In
other words,
>> yeah, that's a great question.
>> And what timeline line would you expect
to see results in?
>> And don't freak out. I'm going to hit
refresh on my uh on my on my StreamYard
because I see that my signal is a little
weak.
>> Okay, go for it. So, first of all, it's
highly unusual to the point of being
unprecedented for a president to
publicly announce that he has authorized
CIA covert action. Right? That is
something. When I was when I was being
called to testify in the Scooter Libby
case, I was told that I wasn't even
allowed to say the words covert action.
Wasn't even allowed to say the words,
let alone to talk about a program. Here
the president of the United States is
talking about like publicly announcing a
covert action program. I never saw
anything like it in my life. So that can
mean a lot of different things. It can
be something as innocuous as
giving a $100,000 to
opposition newspapers to do
investigative reporting. Okay, no big
deal. But it could also be, you know,
training paramilitary forces in the
United States to parachute in and
overthrow the government. It can be
training assassins to take out Nicholas
Maduro. Um, it could be a plan to seize
major intersections in Caracus and hold
them for the likes of Juan Guyaido or
this woman who who apparently won the
election. Um, it can mean a lot of
different things. In this case, I think
the the goal was twofold. The goal was
to actually set in motion the overthrow
of the Venezuelan government, but the
second goal was to so frighten Maduro
that that he at least make contingency
plans to run off somewhere to Cuba most
likely.
>> They're trying to spook him. They're
trying to
>> This is This is a dude who's been
targeted for years now by the United
States. And not to mention his
predecessor, Hugo Chavez, was actually
overthrown for the weekend by the US.
Yes, he um and you know with the
cooperation of the New York Times, not
one of their finest moments. Um
>> but like basically he knows what's in
the mail. He knows what he faces. He's
not spookable, right? I mean he knows.
>> No,
>> he's not he's not too
>> he's not going to run scared.
>> Number one, he will not run scared.
>> Number two,
>> and the Venezuelans are very
nationalistic people, right? They'll
support an unpopular president that they
don't like over an invasion force.
>> 100%. As would most countries.
>> Yes.
>> I would support Donald Trump.
>> Me too.
>> Over, you know, some
>> invading Canadian army. Invading
Canadian Army.
>> Canadian army. Absolutely.
>> [__] off Canadians. Yeah.
>> So, number two, a lot of the people who
would be naturally opposed to Maduro
politically are not in Venezuela.
They're mostly in the United States
working.
And so I I just don't see that this is
going to be
a big problem internally for Maduro. The
the big problem is the prospect of an
American invasion. Well, let's talk
about that because that that that was
definitely something I've been dying to
talk to you about. Like I said, um you
know, in terms of um you know, what's
very interesting and disturbing about
this. I mean, you know, war powers are
assigned exclusively to the US Congress
with very under the Constitution, but
they've been whittleled away for really
for 200 plus years. And now um Trump has
brought this to a new level where
basically he's not even consulting with
Congress anymore about the deployment of
10,000 US troops and the murders of over
30 Venezuelan nationals of whom at least
one appears to have just been a
fisherman. Certainly uh the guy from um
from uh Colombia almost certainly was a
stranded fisherman. Um, and you know, so
basically he wants to do this without
any accountability to the American
people, right? JFK went on national
television and revealed the existence of
spy plane technology to show that Cuba
had Soviet missiles. Uh, and and and
basically was like, "Look, I'm bringing
you to the brink of World War II, World
War II, but here's why and here's what's
going on." This president is not telling
us, he's either lying to us. These are
trendy aragua. None of them are trendy
aragua.
>> No, none of them.
>> None of them. It's like, and you know,
they're bad. They're narotists. There's
no such thing. Um they're bringing drugs
to America. No, they're not. Uh
basically, he he's asserting the right
to just sort of kill people without
identifying them or providing any
evidence about who they were or why they
mean the US harm or why it's legal to do
so. And he's not even consulting with
the gang of eight in in the in in in the
in the Capitol. He's not even, you know,
calling a few representative members of
Congress, uh, and saying like, "Hey, so
here's what I'm up to." There was
apparently a briefing that happened, uh,
I guess a week and a half ago where, um,
someone who came out of it and had seen
all of Trump's information said, "This
isn't at all about um, V, you know,
drugs. We don't care about drugs. This
is about overthrowing Nicolas Maduro.
It's about regime change.
>> Um so I mean what about will Congress,
if they ever get their, you know, get
back into session, are they going to
assert their right to oversee military
action?
>> Absolutely not.
Absolutely. Positively not.
>> Now that's dangerous.
>> It's very dangerous. You know, Congress,
of course, has the constitutional
responsibility to declare war. Congress
has not declared any war since December
the 8th, 1941.
>> That's right.
>> Even even
>> only five times, right?
>> Yeah. In history. And even before the
the first Gulf War, they didn't vote to
declare war on Iraq. They voted to
authorize the use of force.
And then the and then like there's that
uh post 911 authorization to use
military force that basically every
president subsequently has been using to
do whatever the [__] he wants.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Our our our country is in
shambles right now policy-wise. It
really is.
>> And you know I don't blame Donald Trump.
Donald Trump is the stressor. I blame
all the institutions that are supposed
to serve as checks and balances. the
so-called opposition party, the
Democrats, the, you know, the the the
executive the the legislative branch,
which is basically not doing anything,
and even a lot of the judiciary, which I
was for years, I've said was the last
best hope.
>> Yeah.
>> They're they're rolling. Now,
>> just as an example, did you see this
kid? I say kid because he just turned 30
that Donald Trump had named to be the
head of the office of special counsel.
>> Did you see this? And he and he withdrew
yesterday
>> after wasn't available,
>> right? He withdrew yesterday because um
because of uh text messages he had sent
friends of his that just were made
public in which he admitted to having a
Nazi streak.
>> A Nazi
>> one can
who hasn't who hasn't who among us can
truly say we haven't had our Nazi
period. Plus, man, if if you've been if
you've been out of school for six years,
you have no business heading up an
office at the Department of Justice.
>> Well, John, we weren't going to talk
about this, but since you brought up the
DOJ, what about the fact that this
Donald Trump always going for the new
low? Two things. First of all, I'm just
going to mention the ballroom. I didn't
really care about the ballroom at first.
I didn't either.
>> Today, the Washington Post published a
uh a graphic of how big it's going to
be.
>> It's bigger than the White House.
>> Yes. Yes. Like offbalance much. It's
more like we're going to have to call it
like, you know, like Gilligans Island
and the rest. It'll be like the ballroom
and the rest.
>> Yes. Exactly.
>> It's crazy. I mean, it's it's And then
also the DOJ. He's shaking down his own
DOJ. Yes. For a quarter of a billion
dollars. Yes. For his because he's like,
"You [__] sued me and and [__]
with me back during the charged me back
during the Biden years. And I want my
[__] money back. I I want you to make
me whole." It's like basically he's
gangstering his own company. It's like,
hey, nice government I got there. Be a
shame if something wor but it's your
government.
>> When when I saw that he was asking to be
reimbursed $230
million,
I I called Bruce Fine, our our friend
and former deputy attorney general
>> Bruce Fine, and Bruce said, "Oh, yeah,
he can do that."
>> Oh, yeah. There's this there's this
obscure federal law that goes back to
the 19th century that says that if
you're the victim of a of a vindictive
uh
>> prosecution
um you can sue the justice department
and they have to reimburse you
>> but he's the president.
Not to mention Donald at some point when
is enough enough? I mean you've grifted
so much already, right? I mean, like,
you've made billions of dollars. You
never were a billionaire before you
became president, but now you are.
>> Now he's a real billionaire. Yeah.
>> But get getting back to this ballroom,
Ted, it's it's so I I would encourage
people to go to the Washington Post
website today and just look at the
graphic. It's going to make you furious
if if I
>> didn't care up because up until that
point, I was like, well, you know, pre
the White House has been rebuilt more
often than people think. Truman balcony
and so on. Well, the irony here is that
he he tore down the east wing of the
White House. Do you know what the east
wing is?
>> It's the first it's the first lady's
office.
>> Yeah, sorry, Melania.
>> It no longer exists. It's sitting in
rubble
>> on the White House grounds now. Rubble.
>> And by the way, shockingly, he lied and
said that there would not need to be any
demolition whatsoever. I mean, when you
see the size of that thing, this guy,
look, Donald Trump, if he knows
anything, it's about construction and
development. He knew there was going to
have to be a lot of destruction. He and
he said last week, I actually laughed
when I read it. He said, "We're not
going to tear down the East Wing. I love
the East Wing. It's my favorite part of
the White House." I look at it and I
say, "I love this East Wing. It's
fantastic."
And then literally the next day they
tore it down.
>> Oh my god. Yeah. It's it's it's bizarre.
I mean, and it's kind of like, you know,
I mean, look, presidents have put in
bowling alleys, uh, you know, swimming
pools, movie theaters,
>> all sorts of [__] But, I mean, and
that's okay, right? I don't have a
problem. It's just the size of it,
right? It's just sort of like with so
many things with Trump, it's not about
the idea, it's about the execution.
>> That's it.
>> That's it. Yeah. So, I wonder, and I'd
love to hear your thoughts on this,
and I realize it's not important in the
greater scheme of things, but I wonder
if the next president, if it happens to
be a Democrat, is going to tear the
thing down.
>> Nope.
>> Not a chance.
>> They They're going to say, "Look at this
monstrosity. Trump did this." And then
they're going to enjoy the great
benefits of a giant ball.
>> Yesterday, John, I was getting the rig
the the runaround at the post office.
It's too boring to get into why. The
point is it was it was and then I was
like, "Oh, that's right. It's Trump.
They're very short staffed and it's
because of Trump's shitty postmaster
general who he appointed during his
first term." And wait for it, Biden
kept.
>> Yeah. Biden kept.
>> And now we're stuck with him. Or I mean,
Biden kept all sorts of [__] right?
Like Trump got rid of the homeowner uh
deduction for property taxes over 10,000
in order to [__] the people who live in
the blue states. Exactly. Biden kept
that when he came in. I mean, no,
Democrats will keep everything. They
will keep ICE. They'll keep up the ICE
raids. They'll keep it all going.
Nothing will change.
>> That's exactly right.
>> I mean, no, that that no way are they
tearing down that ballroom. I mean,
first of all, they'll they'll want the
ballroom. And besides which, they'll
just sort of say like, "Oh, if we did if
we tore it down, they would accuse us of
wasting taxpayer money and like, you
know, this thing that's already been
built."
>> Yep. I mean, because we've seen this,
John, over and over. Democrats
constantly keep Republican policies and
actions. You know, Republicans don't do
that. They come in, they're like, "Oh,
Affordable Care Act, we're getting rid
of that." Oh, yeah. Right. Hey, real
quickly, and I apologize. It's already
9:34, but I I wanted I wanted to mention
um yesterday afternoon, I started
feeling a little bit better. So, I
walked over to the courthouse which is
very close to my house uh here in
Arlington, Virginia. And I voted I did
early voting.
Um the the only race
>> Thanks for the reminder. I have to do
that too for Mdani.
>> So, the only race of any import here is
is the race for governor. So, it's it's
Abigail Spanberger. And I I worked with
Abby at the CIA. She's perfectly nice
person, but she would in the 1970s and
80s, she would be kind of a middle- of
the road Republican.
>> And then the the current Lieutenant
Governor of Virginia, Winome Windsome
Earl Sears,
is is a nut. She's just a nut. her her
campaign pictures when she was um
running for lieutenant governor four
years ago. Um she's just smiling,
standing, and holding a machine gun like
this. A machine gun.
>> Well, that's like Marjgerie Taylor Green
with her early campaign ads shooting up
the pictures of the Democrats. Yeah. So,
so there was a debate a couple of nights
ago um between the two and and Winome
Earl Sears never shut her flapping gums
through the entire debate. She had to be
repeatedly slapped down because
Spanberger couldn't get a word out. So
Spanberger, in my view, is very
conservative. She's she's from the
conservative wing of the Democratic
party.
and her big thing was that was that um
Earl Sears uh supports discrimination
and
her she said for example when some Earl
Sears doesn't want to allow gay people
to get married and Earl Sears jumps in
and she goes that's not discrimination
that's God's will
and she just kept repeating this every
>> and by the way I would love to be
debating someone like that because I'd
be like, "Do you talk to God? Are you on
psychotropic psychotropic medications?"
Because people who claim to talk to God
are
Oh, and somebody's got a great question
for us. Maybe it's just Robbie. Uh, but
John, what's your opinion on the
Virginia Attorney General's race with
the Democrat talking about killing his
opponent and his family?
>> That's become the biggest issue
>> in the Virginia the statewide Virginia
races. Uh so the the candidate the
Democratic candidate for attorney
general was joking in a text exchange
with a friend of his um and he said
something about like target practice
against Republicans or some stupid thing
like that.
>> I thought he said get rid of
>> Yeah, it was several. It wasn't just
one. He said several several different
things. You know,
my my knee-jerk reaction is shame on
him. He's advocating violence even if
he's doing it doing it uh in what he
says to be a joking manner
>> and in a private conversation.
>> And it's in a private conversation.
>> I mean, come on. We all talk [__]
privately.
>> And I've gotten to the point where my
position is we all talk [__] privately.
The Republicans pull this [__] all the
time. I don't care.
>> Yeah. Look at the rep look at the young
Republicans uh text scandal from last
week.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. So, you know,
the Abby is beating Winmer Sears by six
percentage points right now. Um, this U
Muslim woman uh that the Democrats have
nominated for for a de for sorry um uh
lieutenant governor is winning by the
same six points. And the Jason Mures uh
I forget the other guy's name for
attorney general is a dead heat. I I
don't think, you know, when when Jason
Miis, the Republican, he's
CubanAmerican,
uh, born in Cuba, when he first was
elected attorney general four years ago,
I thought, "Oh my god, there we go. He's
a right-wing extremist. It's going to be
terrible." No, he's been a perfectly
fine uh attorney general.
>> Never in the news enforcing the laws.
>> There's some there's some pearl
clutching in the New Jersey race, too,
>> which is closer than the Virginia race,
>> right? And it's closer only because the
Democratic nominee
>> just isn't a very good candidate.
>> No, she really I mean today the New York
Times ran an op-ed by uh some some
female uh writer that was it's really
depressing. Uh she basically was arguing
that um Hillary Clinton, Kla Harris, and
uh the the New Jersey lady, they're all
victims of sexism.
>> Mikey something. Oh, please give me a
break. And I'm like, these are terrible
candidates.
>> Terrible.
>> I mean, look, here's the thing. Like I
like I posted online in response to
that. Look, you know, Donald Trump when
he campaigned was able to to say
credibly, I understand why you're
pissed. You're pissed because of high
prices. You're pissed because all the
buildings in your downtown area, all
your factories are closed and boarded up
and no one cares. And that sucks.
>> Now, he doesn't have any solutions to
those problems. No. But he's able to say
that,
>> but he tapped the vein,
>> which is one step more than these
Democratic candidates have been able to
do. They're not able to even say, "I see
you and I understand your problems."
They don't even get to that point.
They're literally talking about, you
know, stupid [__] Yeah. You know,
>> Yeah. And this is another thing, too.
The Democrats have not learned their
lesson. And I don't mean their lesson
from 2024.
I mean their lesson from 24, 22, 2018,
16. They haven't learned any lessons.
No,
>> the Democrats are in disarray. They're
in shambles. And they still think that
they're the smartest people in the room.
They know better than you do or better
than I do. And they're just going to
head to defeat after defeat. Um Robbie's
telling us that we have another ad.
>> All right, Robbie, please put it up.
Thank you very much. Um we should we we
do have a lot of ground to cover. So um
let's talk a little bit since we're on
domestic politics. Um, you know, you and
I talked about how no, you know, there's
first of all, uh, the Affordable Care
Act, um, you know, there's it's the
Well, let's read this ad first. Um, if
you haven't already, please make sure
you download the Rumble app. It's free,
simple to use, and the best way to stay
connected to the content you want. Once
you've got it, search for our channel
and hit follow. That way, you'll get a
notification every time we go live. No
missed shows, no extra steps. You can
grab it right now using the link in the
description or the pins live chat.
Download it to your phone and you're
ready to go. And if you prefer watching
on the big screen, Rumble is available
on all major streaming devices and smart
TVs. Just search for Rumble. Follow the
channel and become part of the action.
So, John, we talked about this um afford
on November 1st is a big day. just eight
days from now um or sorry nine days from
now the um people u people who tens of
millions of people who subscribe to
health care through their state and
federal marketplaces are going to see
their premiums skyrocket because the
federal subsidies are going have not
been renewed. Um and that's
>> that's what the subject of the meltdown
is. Does it tell you about the increase
in your premiums?
>> Yeah, it does. And it says, "Listen,
don't throw this away." It says at the
top,
>> "Your coverage may be disrupted if you
don't read this notice and take
immediate action." It says at the very
top and and the and the letter is four
pages long. And the bottom line is
you're screwed.
>> So try to save yourself as best you can,
but you're screwed.
>> Premiums nationally are going to raise
are going to go up by 18% on average if
you're a member of the ACA. the national
uh nationally the average marketplace
consumer will marketplace consumer will
pay 1,94
in annual premiums next year up from
$8.88 88 although I know people who pay
that per month. So I mean I pay more
than 8.88 per month. The situation is
particularly acute in Georgia which
recruit which recorded the second
highest enrollment of any state-run
marketplace this year. 96% of everyone
in Georgia marketplace receive federal
subsidies. Um Georgians are seeing
estimated costs uh double or even
triple. Uh people are are being forced
to choose between their mortgages and
their healthcare. Um, this is going to
be this is what Democrats have been
waiting for in the shutdown. Yeah. And
the pressure is going to build on the on
on the Republicans. I think the
Republicans are going to have to cave.
The only question is how much do they
cave by? Do they renew for one year or
do they renew for two years? Uh,
Democrats want them to renew for two
years and wait for the midterms. Dem uh
Republicans obviously I think they
already know in their heart of hearts
that they're going to have to renew for
a year. Um the the Republican
negotiating point here has been absurd.
They've said agree to reopen the
government and then we'll negotiate.
It's like no
>> the Democrats have by the balls on this
issue. That's not how it works. Yeah.
Finally. It's right.
>> Yeah. Finally. Um ye yesterday this
became the second longest uh uh shutdown
in American history. Uh it will become
the longest shutdown like in a couple of
days I think.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Just
>> just a couple of days.
>> And I think it's it could go on but I
mean yeah definitely if I'm the if I'm
uh you know Schumer and Jeff I'm just
like everything is just fine
>> because Congress is still getting paid.
>> You know they exempt themselves from
these
>> of course
>> these other other laws. And of and and
of course Trump is finding is uh shaking
down the the sofa cushions to look for
money for the military.
>> Yeah.
>> Does the CIA get paid under this or is
>> just Okay.
>> No. And the thing about the CIA too,
nobody at the CIA gets paid, but
everybody at the CIA is considered a a
necessary um employee.
>> So you're forced to work.
>> Literally everybody at the CIA. When I
was in Bahrain uh in in 95,
uh
it was this what is until the other day
was the second longest shutdown ever.
And the ambassador declared everybody in
the embassy an essential employee except
the nurse. The nurse was the only one
that didn't have to come in.
That's I've got to comment on something
that Tammy said. Nobody comments on my
political stuff on Facebook. Um, let me
just say, um, Facebook throttles all
political content. Um, you know,
whenever, um, I post, uh, my political
cartoons or columns on Facebook, they go
crazy on X, but on Facebook, nobody sees
them. I get like three likes. Um, I put
a picture of Clovis up there, thousands
of likes. I mean, granted, Clovis is
more appealing than my politics, but
still. I mean, and they've said that.
They said that they throttle all
political content,
>> so it's not like a conspiracy or
anything. Um, so government shutdown,
we're going to say, can Democrats snatch
defeat from the jaws of victory here?
>> Uh, I I don't think so. I don't trust
the Democrats. I think that Hakee Jeff
is a clown and uh and Chuck Schumer is
corrupt and I don't think there is any
leadership in the Democratic party. What
do you think?
>> Um, well, no. I mean, I I mean, what I
was trying to say is like I I can they
[__] this up? Um, I mean, Democrats are
sitting pretty. Could they [__] this up
and undernegotiate and underleverage
this?
>> Absolutely.
>> They could. Yeah,
>> absolutely. Yes,
>> they could really blow it. But, I mean,
you know, right now that the Republicans
are starting to finally feel the heat on
something, you know. I mean, Donald
Trump, this is eight years overdue, but
he in 2016, he promised to come up with
a plan to to repeal and replace aid the
ACA. Ain't nothing yet. And I I mean I
think the bottom line is I I don't know
what the answer to this is. Either the
Republican party is split on this issue
because like MTG says we've got to do
something about it or Republicans in
general just don't care about
healthcare. And I'm leaning I lean more
toward the latter. But what do you
think?
>> Yeah, I think the Democrats probably
consider them themselves fortunate that
they have uh the ACA as an issue.
Otherwise, there is no issue,
>> right? Um, and that's the only thing
that's going to save them as this thing.
>> And it is a shitty It's a shitty plan.
It's just that it's better than no plan.
>> Yeah, without a doubt.
>> Uh, C Morris, thanks for the dollar. Did
we Did you all see where a former J6
pardon was arrested for threatening to
kill Hakee Jeff?
>> Yes,
>> I did see that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, so many of these
people that Trump pardoned um have
gotten in trouble since their since
their pardons and their release from
prison. One was shot and killed uh in a
shootout with a cop in Indiana.
>> Of course, there were Could that be
Could that just be simply that there
were thousands of them and if you
randomly select Yeah. 3,000 people,
>> you know, eight of them are going to get
into trouble with the law.
>> Yes, I think that's it. I think that's
it. I mean, it does remind me a little
bit about the four [__] that Bernard
gets, the uh subway vigilante shot in
the mid1 1980s here in New York City in
the subway. Yes.
>> And then one of them was later, you
know, there were liberals who were like
they were just underprivileged youths.
And one of them got caught raping his
85year-old
neighbor on the roof of his housing
project. Lovely fellow.
>> Oh lord.
Oh my god.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a special place in
hell for people like that.
>> For sure. And it's kind of like after
all that I was kind of like I'm on team
Bernie Gats. Besides which I always
thought I always thought that the most
interesting moment there was that like
when the cops showed up they said which
way did he go
>> and everyone who was on the car, nobody
who knew him, they all said he went that
way when it was the other way.
>> Yeah.
>> So they saw what happened and uh they
all sided here. Um, so, okay, let's
let's get into um the uh I'm I'm super
interested in this uh genocide thing.
Genocide 2.0, as I put it in the
thumbnail. So, Israel I mean, it's
unbelievable. I guess it's not
unbelievable, but Israel is blocking aid
into the Gaza Strip again. Now, the
whole point of the well, a big point of
the 20point plan was the aid was going
to be completely restored um and it was
going to flow in and flood the zone. Um
which by the way would put a major crimp
into those criminal gangs who've been
stealing aid. Um so basically the uh the
the the border crossings, two out of
seven of them are open, five out of
seven are closed. Aid trucks are are
stranded. Um, UNRA was supposed to be
allowed back in. They're not being
allowed back in. A bunch of NOS's are
that are that have long experience, very
reputable, are not being allowed back
in. Um, so basically there's a
ceasefire.
I don't get this. So, John, explain this
to me. Israel signs assigns a ceasefire,
but they're still shooting and killing
and blowing.
>> Well, you you called this you called
this weeks ago. You said that the
Israelis always, always, always violate
the ceasefire and they violate it
quickly and they did it within hours of
>> over and over with air strikes,
shootings, you name it. Right. Then
also, um, they said they're allow
they're going to allow aid in. They
don't allow the aid in. Yeah.
>> Um, I mean, it's kind of like,
>> what is this? What is this [__]
agreement? Well, we're moving on to
phase two. Y'all haven't done phase one.
No, no. In fact, um, uh, JD Vance is in
Israel right now, and I just got a push
notification 15 minutes ago or so that
Marco Rubio has arrived in Israel as
well,
>> presumably to tell the Israelis to get
with the program.
>> He even said like, "Oh, I'm not here to
babysit the the ceasefire." I'm like, "I
think you are."
>> Yeah, I think that's exactly why you're
there. Yes.
>> And by the way, I'm all for it.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
>> Um, so yeah. So, let's um Well,
>> may I add something, too? You know,
Tucker Carlson has been more and more
outspoken about Israel and he's making a
lot of enemies,
especially on the on the pro-Zionist
right. And um
lately he's been talking about both the
notion of of greater Israel as well as
this Zionist extremist plan to blow up
the the Dome of the Rock, the third
holiest site in Islam, and to build what
would be the third temple, right? The
the first temple on the on the
>> Those people are crazy. They're crazy.
But it's it's entered the mainstream of
Israeli scholarship.
>> Chiron visiting
the the Dome of the Rock was enough to
trigger the second inif.
>> Yep. That's right. To blow it up and and
he said the other day and and I agree
with him wholeheartedly.
>> To to destroy the Dome of the Rock would
be the event that starts World War II.
>> Yes.
>> Easy as that. And by the way, I think it
would probably be the end, the beginning
of the end of the Israeli government and
all of its support. I think it what
would happen to them in a way I hope
they do it because it'll be just like
what happened to the Taliban after they
blow up the bamean statues,
>> bamean statues
>> and like and the whole world up until
that point. People forget um you know,
yeah, they were, you know, obviously a
very isolated regime. Sure.
>> But
>> they were the world was starting to warm
to them, right? like the Clinton
administration was actually paying
Taliban official salaries. Uh they were
we were funding um you know opium
eradication in Afghanistan. We were
flirting with this uh trans Afghanistan
pipeline project. That's right.
>> Um we were you know we were we we we
flew Taliban emissaries to Houston to
meet with with uh you know with the
bushies. Yep.
>> Early on. So we were start things were
starting to maybe warm up. And then they
pulled that and then that was from that
point on they were dead to us.
>> Yes. Exactly. Yes.
>> It's interesting, right? I mean because
the
>> it's fascinating.
>> Mulla Omar said like, "Well, you guys
care about these, you know, old rocks
more than you care about the people who
are affected by sanctions." Point taken.
But he's also right. Like we do care
about old rocks a lot. Yeah. In this
case, we and we care about old religious
buildings, too.
>> That's right. That's just the way it is.
Sorry if that's offensive, but that's
just a fact of life.
>> Yeah. Human psychology is what it is. Y
>> um do we want to uh talk about Well, we
should. I mean, it's perfect timing.
Russia and Ukraine.
>> So,
>> yeah, we have to.
>> So, it looks like um obviously So, I'm
I'm at a little bit of at a loss here. I
mean, you know, we are definitely
reduced as Americans to Kremlin, like
reading between the lines of isvestia
every day to find out what's really
true, right? Yes.
>> So,
>> um, so Sergey Lavro, foreign minister of
of Russia, uh, under Putin, called Marco
Rubio and basically said, "Look, our
position hasn't really changed and Trump
is misc is miscatategorizing our
ability. Trump just wants to freeze the
conflict at its current lines and just
say, "Okay, that's it. These are the new
borders. Maybe later on you can do some
land swaps, but for now, this is it.
Line of control just like Kashmir, and
that's how we're doing it." Um, and then
Trump was like, "No, no, no, no. I want
this to be that's it. This is the war.
It's over." Russia said, "Our position
hasn't changed." So, they had this call.
They there had been plans for Putin to
go meet Trump and then Trump is going to
get to say, "Look, I solved my ninth
war, 10th war, whatever he's gonna say."
Um,
>> yeah.
>> And um and and that that's now on hold.
Is Trump now pissed at Putin or is this
just sort of like is this a big deal or
is this just sort of like a delay and
these things happen?
Um,
you know, Trump wants a deal because
it's going to make him look good and he
thinks it's going to get him the Nobel
Peace Prize. Of course, a deal would be
good for the two sides, but but
Zalinski, despite being, you know,
regularly beaten about the face and head
by Trump and Vance, um, said, "We're not
giving up territory." Now, we've all
been saying from the beginning that
that's likely the only way there's going
to be peace on this issue is they're
going to have to give up territory,
>> of course.
>> But I think I think Trump accepted that
in this last meeting with uh with
Zilinski and and that's why the the
summit in Budapest has been indefinitely
delayed.
>> So what so what next?
Well, the the counter proposal was a
ceasefire with an armistice line. So,
the Russians presumably could de facto
control what they've got on the
Ukrainian side of the border. Now, even
though that that
territory would not formally become
Russia, that's going to have to include
Crimea, of course, which is a real
sticking point for the Ukrainians. But
the bottom line is I was talking to
Peter Kousnik about this the other day.
Peter is the history professor at uh
American University, chairman of the
nuclear studies program. He's one of the
country's leading experts on Russia. And
um and he says that the Ukrainians are
are losing, right? They they just can't
keep this up. There aren't enough
>> clearly
>> people to fight. They're snatching old
men off the street. literally snatching
them off the street and just sending
them to the front lines,
>> fleeing when they can.
>> And the young people are fleeing. They
just can't keep this up. There's going
to have to be some kind of negotiated
settlement. And whatever the settlement
happens to be at the end,
>> the Ukrainians are going to come out on
the on the short side of it.
>> And Trump doesn't want to and Trump does
not want to give uh these cruise
missiles to uh Ukraine. that would so
worsen the situation to give the
Ukrainians Tomahawk cruise missiles that
it would risk it would risk involving
NATO. It would risk, you know, a
tactical nuclear strike on Ukrainian
positions.
It's a it's a very bad idea.
>> Want to thank very generous donation
from Kevin Cronin720. 20 bucks over on
YouTube.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much. He said you are
amazing. I don't know who you are. I
want to say the plural you. I hope.
>> Oh, I appreciate that.
>> Uh question for John from Praasmataz.
>> Uh John, you said that you were going to
talk more about foxes. You mentioned it
then mentioned something else first.
Just wondering what species maybe tell
hard to tell at a distance.
>> No, I come they run right in front of
your car as they're trying to cross this
dirt track. They had huge ears which I
had never seen before. And I saw rabbits
with these gigantic
ears that are standing right up. They're
like desert rabbits or the desert hair
or whatever.
>> Yeah, I was going to say I think those
are hairs.
>> Yeah. Uh but yeah, there they were
different from the foxes. You know,
there there's this
the cook at the resort told us not to
worry about not finishing dinner because
there was a fox that lived on the
grounds and the fox would just eat our
scraps.
>> Well, cute. The fox would always poop
right where I come out to go to my mini
fridge every freaking night. And so
these poor ladies had to clean up the
poop. Um it it was a desert fox like you
see in Sinai or uh or in Afghanistan.
They're they're very small. They're gray
and they only come out at night.
Fasmataz says it sounds like a fenic so
fox n I am not a fox I'm not a fox
connoisseur so
>> there it is let me see
>> well
>> yeah that's it that's it yeah
>> that's it okay that's
>> yeah very cool
>> confirmed all right cool well guys uh
here we go how do we American sweetheart
asks how do we make it on small
donations do you have any larger donors
you have to uh no we don't we're
currently only making it on small
donations and of course uh what Rumble
is is paying us from uh you know the
views and the ads. Uh so basically the
you know it's it's really truly up up to
you guys and we're moving in the right
direction but we are definitely this is
not a living yet um and so uh but it is
moving in the right direction. So that's
thanks to you guys and that's great
question. Um, thanks everyone and that's
a perfectly good time and good place to
end the show. We're here tomorrow. Uh,
we will be here Thursday 9:00 a.m. Um,
as we are Monday through Friday. Please
watch us on Rumble. Please like, follow,
share, subscribe to the show. Thank you
so much for joining us, John. So good to
have you back. Robbie, good to see you,
Ted.
>> Thank you for so much for producing as
always. And uh stick around for the TMI
show with me and Manila Chan coming
right up if you're on Rumble, but you
can pop over from YouTube, too. Bye.